## Robert J.Clemmer

302 Audubon St. Staunton VA 24401 (540) 292-2391 clemmer.robert.j@gmail.com

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Seasoned Professional who undertakes new challenges, leads and mentors others, and provides exceptional service. Experience with managing, innovating, and leading. Able to collaborate with others and independently create and launch new projects. Always willing to learn.

#### Skills:

Technical Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL Front-end Libraries: React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Handlebars.js Back-end Technologies: Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Mongoose, RESTful API Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexDB

# **Professional Experience**

## **Arborist**, Queen City Silvicutlure, Staunton VA

Nov 2022 - present

- Assisted with pruning, tree removal, and tree planting.
- Operated and maintained arboriculture equipment, ensuring safety protocols were followed.
- Assisted in the maintenance of equipment and heavy machinery.

# Farm Manager, Project Grows, Staunton VA

Mar 2021 - Nov 2022

- Grew over 25,000 lbs of food for the Staunton, Augusta County, Waynesboro area.
- Operated a 40 person CSA spanning June October.
- Adopted No-Till practices to increase soil health
- Managed the Youth Leaders in Agriculture program, a team of 5 students who were at the farm

# Executive Associate, The Arcadia Project, Staunton, VA

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Volunteer position with Arcadia Project, a local nonprofit seeking to revitalize two historic buildings to create community through culture. Helped the organization pursue Phase 1, restoring the building facades, an old movie marquee, and raising \$30,000 for the back roof of an old vaudeville theater. Met with donors, organized volunteers, and designed promotional media.

# Admissions Counselor, Mary Baldwin University, Staunton, VA

Aug 2018 - Aug 2020

Recruited students from Southwest and Southside VA to MBU's biggest class. Contacting families and answering questions about academic options.

- Traveled for two seasons throughout rural Southwest and Southside VA, meeting with school counselors, teachers, students, and families.
- Collaborating with the Spencer Center for Civic and Global Engagement, organized and led an Alternative Spring Break trip focusing on food justice.

**Program Specialist,** *University of Georgia, Rock Eagle 4-H Center*, Eatonton, GA Jan 2016 - Aug 2018 Trained staff to teach 7 classes. Managed teams to maintain <sup>1</sup>/<sub>4</sub> acre garden, our Pioneer site, and canoeing program areas; Oversaw the history program and garden program.

- Developed a curriculum for new Garden/Botany Class
- Wrote grant application and received \$1990 from Watson Brown Foundation for Rock Eagle's pioneer site
- Incorporated goats, farming, and blacksmithing into Living History program
- Helped organize Seed Swap targeted to gardeners, farmers, and beginners in Middle Georgia

**Environmental Educator**, *University of Georgia*, *Rock Eagle 4-H Center*, Eatonton, GA Jan - Nov 2015 Provided instruction to elementary and secondary students utilizing Georgia state education Standards of Excellence. Assisted students in developing awareness, knowledge and appreciation for the natural environment while cultivating self-confidence, critical reasoning skills, and sense of environmental stewardship. Taught over 20 classes including herpetology, Native American studies, forest ecology, lake assessment, ornithology, and team initiative courses.

• Managed facility food waste for composting exhibits and developed lessons for a garden class

**Stewardship Crew Leader**, *Lancaster County Conservancy*, Lancaster PA

April - Nov 2014
Supervised a crew of four to monitor, rehabilitate, and conserve wild lands and preserves throughout Lancaster County.

Directed volunteers during Conservancy Work Weekends.

- Developed and facilitated environmental education hikes for students focusing on watershed studies
- Represented LCC at the Susquehanna Permaculture Conference.
- Organized and coordinated a Volunteer day with the Pennsylvania Dutch Council and Cycling for Conservation

## Guide/Dog Musher, Alaska Dog Sled Tours, Willow, AK

Sept 2013 - April 2014

Provided an interpretive experience for guests, accommodating their needs in subzero conditions. Responsible for caring and feeding 100 Alaskan huskies at an Iditarod winning kennel. Worked with the Chugiak Mushing Club and the Alaska State Parks to clear and maintain public trails (*mushing dogs with a chainsaw on my sled*).

**District Executive**, *Boy Scout of America*, *Garden State Council*, Westampton, NJ Sept 2012 - Sept 2013 Provided service to over 1,500 youth and hundreds of volunteers through Burlington County. Developed relationships with schools, civic organizations, and religious organizations to promote Scouting and the outdoors. Worked with volunteers to coordinate camporees, recruiting nights, training opportunities, and fundraising events. Responsible for recruiting, coaching, and guiding a volunteer board and executing an annual fund drive raising more that \$27,000.

- Working with Burlington County Special Services School, coordinated outdoor program for inner city youth from Trenton, NJ
- Organized First annual and Second Annual Wine Tasting event, generating over \$10,000 for outdoor program

**Associate Director of Conservation**, *Philmont Scout Ranch*, Cimarron, NM Mar 2012 - Aug 2012 Oversaw and managed the Conservation Camper program for over 20,000 participants. Trained and managed a 20 person team. Assisted in Department Training, emphasizing project management, risk management, safety, and environmental education to over 90 staff. Coordinated logistics and monitored progress of six different worksites. Started a small garden for Conservation Leadership.

Americorps Corpsmember, Coconino Rural Environment Corps, Flagstaff, AZ Oct 2010 – Apr 2011 Worked with the National Park Service, National Forest Service, and the Bureau of Land Management to construct a sustainable trail, rehabilitate wilderness areas, and control invasive species.

#### **Education**

**Full Stack Coding Bootcamp** 

University of Richmond, 2023

**Bachelor of Arts in History, Classical Studies** 

Hampden Sydney College, Hampden Sydney, VA, 2009

Patrick Henry Scholar, Eta Sigma Phi, Union Philanthropic Literary Society

#### **Certifications and Awards**

**Shenandoah Permaculture Institute** Permacutlure Design Certificate - Nov 2022

Leave No Trace Trainer - May 2011

University of Georgia Cooperative Extension Master Gardener - April 2017

Wilderness First Aid - Oct 2010

Eagle Scout - Aug 2005

#### **Personal Interests**

Trail running, playing mandolin and accordion, backpacking, camping, gardening, climbing, canoeing,